John Hirsch V

US Citizen | St. Louis, MO | jhirschthe5@gmail.com | (757)-344-7496 | jhirschv | GitHub | John Hirsch V | LinkedIn PORTFOLIO

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software developer skilled in Python, Java, and JavaScript. Experience in full-stack web development using Spring Boot, Django, and React. Strong communication and goal setting skills honed from several years working as a personal trainer. Pursuing developer roles in a technical environment.

EXPERIENCE

BestTech (Java/React Full Stack Web App) BestTech | GitHub

Jul 2024 - Oct 2024

Team Member

- Developed a comprehensive eCommerce application with a fully functioning admin dashboard
- Applied Agile methodologies throughout the Software Development Lifecycle, utilizing Git and GitHub
- Created a product recommendation machine learning algorithm using Python and Scikit-learn
- Utilized Shadcn/ui and Tailwind CSS to develop a modern user interface
 Tech Stack: Java (Spring Boot), React.js, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, shadcn/ui

Train.io (Python/React Full-Stack Web App) <u>Train.io</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

Jan 2024 - Jun 2024

Creator

- Implemented an artificial intelligence powered workout creator through OpenAI's API
- Developed a comprehensive workout journal to track users' workout weights, reps, videos, and notes
- Integrated Django REST Framework to create RESTful APIs with data validation to ensure data integrity
- Designed a fully functional personal training system, allowing trainers to manage clients effectively
- Designed an aesthetic dashboard with **data visualization** for monitoring fitness progress and achievements **Tech Stack**: Python (Django), React.is, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, shadcn/ui

Discourse - Chat Application (Python/React) Discourse | GitHub

Jan 2024 – May 2024

- Created a real-time chat application, allowing users to sign up and chat with friends
- Used Django Channels and WebSockets to manage real-time messaging
- Designed an interactive **React frontend** that is fully **mobile responsive**
- Integrated JWT authentication for secure API requests and user logins
 Tech Stack: Python (Django), React.js, WebSockets, Django Channels, Libsodium.js

Cloud Code — Online Code Execution Project

Jan 2024 - Mar 2024

- Created a web-based coding environment that allows users to write code that is executed remotely
- Utilized the **Docker SDK** to spin up **Docker containers** to execute user submitted code
- Developed a frontend with React and Material UI, using the Monaco text editor react package
- Tech Stack: Python, Django, Docker, React.js, Tailwind CSS, Material UI

Social Network - CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript Project

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

- Developed a social network platform with interactive posts and a follow/follower system
- Utilized Django's ORM to manage user data and interactions with efficient database queries
- Incorporated asynchronous JavaScript API requests for single-page application functionality
 Tech Stack: Python (Django), JavaScript, WebSockets

SKILLS

Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL, Spring Boot, Django, React.js, Node.js, Git, Docker, AWS, PostgreSQL, MySQL

EDUCATION

Launch Code Web Development - Java Bootcamp Old Dominion University Bachelor of Science St. Louis, Missouri Graduated Aug 2024 Norfolk, Virginia Graduated May 2023